[Music]
heart hi my name is Andrew Sweeney
welcome to my podcast today I'm going to
talk about slavo Z Zack and his article
in the independent on Jordan Peterson
incidentally this is the most popular
medium article I've written so far and I
believe that Z's ech read it and
responded I'm going to put links to that
that response after I can't say for
certain that he was responding to this
particular article but it seemed to be a
point-by-point rebuttal in many ways so
again I could be wrong here and I also
want to say that I enjoy Z's ex work
very much and I just thought his article
in the independent was quite weak
so here goes so I always like slavo Z
check last J I read three massive tones
of his work getting lost in the forest
of Z Zack is like being in a dense
jungle eventually you get to a clearing
and discover a flash of insight even if
most of the time you feel somewhat lost
in an impenetrable tangle of lakhani and
theory and provocation I kept reading
him for those flashes of insight and yet
I never really got what he stood for his
essence remained obscure to me Z Zack is
a master storyteller a great comedian a
feast of words perhaps a black magician
but this year I also discovered Jordan B
Peterson's work and I've often meditated
on the differences between the two men
not just their political differences
Peterson calls himself a classic liberal
and Z Zack a communist but there are
essential differences as personality
types as well Peterson's work on the big
five personality traits has helped me
some in this respect
Zizek and Peterson are obviously high in
trait openness and IQ that is creativity
and abstraction but Peterson is far more
conscientious and Z Zack is far more
Radek the differences can be seen in
body language Peterson suits and
gentlemanly demeanor versus Z's ex
designer t-shirts and wild hair Z's ex
apparent indifference to personal
hygiene and constant twitching versus
Peterson suits and poised charismatic
presence of course while grooming and
style might seem like an irrelevant
subject it is also analogous to how they
both write and talk Z's ex comes up with
a huge book every couple of years
whereas Peterson spent many years
writing and rewriting his first book
maps of meaning Peterson has said that
he wrote and rewrote every sentence of
that book over ten times to get each
word perfect Z's Eck on the other hand
seems to write at the speed he thinks
and speaks in a voluminous cloud in
interviews Zee Zack tends to swarm his
opponent in this cloud
whereas Peterson while he talks a lot
appears to listen deeply to what the
other is saying recently Z Zack wrote an
uncharacteristically short hit piece on
Peterson in the independent which
surprised the hell out of me for a
couple of reasons firstly he obviously
hadn't done any research and he had
fallen for every kind of caricature
which the media has propped up against
Peterson Peterson has described as an
alt right figure who represents the
liberal silent majority a sort of quack
psychologist with no real scientific
credentials the appearance of cold
scientific argumentation he writes
totally blind to the inner antagonisms
and inconsistencies of the liberal
project itself basically Z Zach was
parroting the usual Marxist idea about
the inner contradictions of capitalism
and was straw Manning Peterson without
having even looked into Peterson's
scientific credentials or a serious
study of Nietzsche Hume totalitarianism
evolutionary biology and the psychology
of the Bible how disappointing and yet
at the same time how revealing why
woodsy Zack writes such a poorly
researched propaganda piece why wouldn't
he make a serious attack on any weakness
in Peterson's actual ideas
the cynic might say he did it because
Peterson is a sujud Azure or he did it
for money
even if Peterson were a monster of the
alt-right who would be wrong to say that
he is not sophisticated a dedicated
monster with a compelling thesis Z Zack
could have asked why doesn't Peterson
come out against an r and individualism
isn't Peterson a bit of a social
Darwinist while making a compelling
argument against his actual ideas
instead Z Zack accused Peterson of being
an anti-immigrant transphobic and a
conspiracy theorists all of which after
having read maps of meaning and listened
to hundreds of classroom lectures of dr.
Peterson I don't find a scrap of
evidence for as I wrote in my first
medium article on Peterson hilariously
since Peterson is falsely caricatured
again and again is all trite he has
never actually voiced a particularly
Republican view he has never said he is
against gay marriage gun control or
abortion neither as he said he is
anti-immigration or pro death penalty
incidentally Z's ekiz pro-capital
punishment Peterson has however had the
guts to dialogue with people on the
right which means he acts in accordance
with his principles of dialogue and
humanism free speech is also the freedom
to say nothing and not be roped into
virtue signaling of all kinds Peterson
has had the composure to keep to the
subject matter at hand which is a civil
rights issue of compelled speech I've
been wanting Peterson to have real
conversations with people on the left
for a while and I'm gratified to see
that he has talked to Russell Brand
recently perhaps I want this because I'm
a temperamental lefty which corresponds
to my score on the big five personality
test designed by Peterson and his team
I'm also high in openness and a bit
neurotic perhaps this is one reason why
I resonate with Z's AK in the first
place along with my love of provocateurs
and comedians Peterson has spoken with
many comedians I hope he will talk to
Z's Eck in the future and I can agree
with zis Eck that the left doesn't have
its house in order
especially since the left
Ziza in this case can't make a serious
well reasoned argument against his
enemies he obviously could if he hadn't
been so lazy or even know his enemies
are Ziza like Kathy Newman addresses not
Peterson but a caricature recently in an
interview I heard these that criticized
the Marxist preference for action over
philosophy I am a good Hegelian if you
have a good theory forget about reality
he says again
this is a provocation it is funny it is
very postmodern post-modernism is a
critique of reified truth and depicts
authenticity as the biggest fakery
fiction is the only reality reality is
for the over earnest that is what zis ik
is saying this couldn't be more opposed
to Peterson's emphasis on logos or truth
speech what matters to Z deck is theory
and fictions not logos Peterson on the
other hand believes that speaking the
truth and not telling lies is the road
to salvation of course these decades a
provocateur and a good one here is
another because the horror of communism
Stalinism is not that bad people do bad
things they always do it's the good
people do horrible things thinking they
are doing something great okay but then
why does eASIC still consider himself a
communist and wax poetically about the
dictatorship of the proletariat what
about the internal contradictions of
communism what about all those horrors
Peterson often criticizes those who say
that wasn't real communism because every
actual communist country has had ghoul
eggs and concentration camps so what is
real communism woodsies XA it doesn't
exist but theory is more important than
facts anyway finally if you don't want
to read the big books of Z Z ik as I
have although admittedly there are a lot
of fun someone has boiled down his
thought to its essence on a Twitter feed
attributed to him note I have since
learned that the Twitter account is fake
however I do believe they are still his
words for instance I hope I don't
disappoint you but there is no master
I'm afraid you have the shocking
realization is that the throne is empty
the self is the fetishized illusion of a
substantial core of subjectivity where
in reality there is nothing these are
some quotes from zis ik z zack is a
great intellectual comedian i'll given
that but the winner is Peterson Peterson
is actually leading a real revolution of
the proletariat